MOHAMED SHAHEN

98-15 Horace Harding Expy Apt 17F Corona, NY 11368 (646)387-2720 m.shahen1@gmail.com

INTRODUCTION

Mid-level education and engineering professional with more than 7 years of combined experience and a master's degree in optical physics. Educational experience includes teaching college-level physics as well as tutoring in math and physics up to and including college-level. Technical engineering experience includes engineering design, development, technical support and client interaction. Seeking opportunities that will allow me to contribute as well as enhance and broaden my expertise.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida – Orlando, FL College of Optics and Photonics M.S. Optical Science and Engineering Master of Science received in May 2010 Fordham University – Bronx, NY
Fordham College at Rose Hill
B.S. Engineering Physics
Bachelor of Science received in May 2007
Magna Cum Laude

SKILLS

Communication Skills:

- Strong English communication, presentation, writing, and reasoning skills.
- Additional languages: fluency in Arabic, prior studies in Spanish and French.
- Professional instructing, tutoring, mentoring, and customer interaction skills.

Computer Skills:

- Proficiency in using Microsoft Windows, Office suite, Adobe Photoshop, and Adobe Acrobat.
- Typing speed of approximately 60 words per minute.
- Strong and proven problem-solving/troubleshooting skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fordham University Physics Department, Bronx, NY

Adjunct Instructor of Physics 01/2013 – Present

• Teach the evening *General Physics II* and *Physics II Lab* courses, including lecturing, administering exams, and grading.

Seniors Professional Training Center, Cairo, Egypt

Tutor of Physics 06/2011 – 10/2012 (1 year, 4 months)

• Tutored students in physics at the levels of college and high-school.

Personal Leave of Absence, Alexandria, Egypt 07/2011 – 10/2012 (1 year, 6 months)

• Helped care for chronically paralyzed father and looked after family in wake of events in Egypt.

Siemens Energy Inc (Through CDI Business Solutions), Orlando, FL

Advanced Engineer Contractor 02/2011 – 04/2011 (2 months)

• Supported design and development of optical probes intended for live optical monitoring of gas turbine blades.

Northrop Grumman Laser Systems, Apopka, FL

Lead Optical/Laser Engineer 06/2007 – 12/2010 (3 years, 6 months)

- Supported optical engineering through design and development of optical- and laser-based military products.
- Accomplishments include 24 consecutive months of on-time unit delivery, significantly reduced rework and failure rates of products, introducing new measurement functionality to the production floor to streamline operations, and training technicians in the use of best practices.
- Exercised and enhanced my presentation skills through the frequent creation of technical reports for customers and internal engineering, including trade-off studies, experiment/test procedures, and user guides.

Acolyte Industries Inc, Manhattan, NY

LED Applications Engineer 06/2005 – 06/2007 (2 years)

- Conducted extensive characterization tests on LED decorative illumination products.
- Enhanced the company's technical asset library by creating a comprehensive *Technical Product Specifications Manual* covering the company's entire illumination product line.
- Accomplishments include expanding the company's marketing capabilities by designing display cases to showcase the different products for clients as well as by creating different types of product literature like sales brochures, product manuals and illustrated installation guides.
- Successfully managed applications support by working with clients to address their technical issues and identify technical solutions to their needs using the available product line.

Fordham University Physics Department, Bronx, NY

Tutor of Physics 09/2005 – 05/2007 (2 academic years)

• Tutored students in college-level physics.

Outbox Technologies Inc, Brooklyn, NY

Sales Specialist 05/2004 – 05/2005 (1 year)

- Used my excellent communication, presentation, and interpersonal skills in driving sales of the company's telecommunications product line by creating strong relationships with clients, frequently leading to repeat business.
- Successfully demonstrated mentoring skills, multi-tasking and decision-making abilities, as well as efficiency at managing self and others by training and developing newly-recruited sales representatives for the company.

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Northrop Grumman Laser Systems Commander's Coin for 24 consecutive months of on-time product delivery: December, 2010
- Member of the Phi Beta Kappa National Honor Society
- Member of the National Scholars Honor Society
- Victor F. Hess Award for Excellence in Physics: April, 2007
- Fordham University Dean's list: 03/04, 04/05, 05/06, 06/07 academic years
- National Dean's List Published Biography: 05/06 academic year
- Fordham University Emerging Leaders (F.U.E.L.) Certificate of Merit: 03/04 academic year

2 of 2